SVETLANA VAZ

+1(213) 422-6330 / +1(213) 342-1679

http://linkedin.com/in/svetvaz www.svetlanavaz.asuscomm.com

Milpitas, CA 95035 svetvaz@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Data Science and Software Engineering professional with experience in building ensembles using supervised and unsupervised machine learning algorithms and NLP for text classification, sentiment analysis and regression (Naive Bayes, Linear Regression, SVM, Random Forest, XgBoost). Highly interested in predictive analytics and applying Big Data to machine learning problems

CORE EXPERTISE

- Machine Learning Algorithms
- Natural Language Processing
 Design Patterns
- Server Side Development
- Agile, Scrum
- Data Structures & Algorithms

INTERESTS

• Deep Learning • Big Data • Recommender Systems

WORK EXPERIENCE

DropThought Inc. Santa Clara, California Jan 2014 - Present

Data Scientist / Full Stack Engineer

- Currently building a MultiLingual text and sentiment classification engine
 - ✓ Uses IBM Models for machine translation
- Built an End to End Text and Sentiment Classification Engine using an Ensemble of various strong machine learning algorithms and voting mechanisms on feedback using scikit-learn and spark MLib
 - ✓ Accuracy achieved >93%
 - ✓ Automated vigorous data pre processing before running the final Classification Algorithm
 - ✓ Classification Algorithm is both space & time efficient
- Developed the server side for the core instant feedback capturing product used by Enterprise clients such as Cisco, Adobe, Sony Playstation, Juniper
 - ✓ Wrote the Node is layer to communicate between the API and the front end built using Angular is
 - ✓ Introduced a security layer to encrypt data both at the front end and on the transport layer
- Integrated an analytics software tool 'Tableau' into DropThought
 - ✓ Automated data updates using a MySql connection
 - ✓ Embedded tableau results onto a dashboard for enhanced visualization & added a security layer to restrict access to authorized users
- Developed an automated API testing suite with a web interface
 - ✓ Built a robust testing suite to test every API call using Frisby, js, Jasmine, Node. js, Express, Html 5, CSS and Javascript thus reducing manual testing effort by 75%
- Developed a sentiment based language analysis web app using Natural Language Processing
 - ✓ Eliminated manual topic and theme extraction
 - ✓ Created word cloud of uni, bi and trigrams of the input feed using NLTK, d3.js, Node.js and Express

Heal the Bay Santa Monica, California

May 2012 - Dec 2013 **Volunteer Force.com Developer**

- Redesigned and Normalized the salesforce database that stored account/contact details of donors
 - ✓ Developed apex triggers, classes and workflows from scratch
 - ✓ Salesforce API Integration and report generation

Barclays Bank PLC, Credit Cards Pune, India

Aug 2010-Sep 2011

- Solution Architect
- Recommended future state business requirements, processes, technologies, applications and information systems to create the 'to-be' target from an 'as-is' baseline
 - ✓ Performed gap analysis and cost vs. effort estimation
- Defined & validated technical requirements & architecture quality attributes and accordingly recommended technical solutions for application integration
 - ✓ Provided high level solution for client-server and N-tier critical applications

Swisscom IT Services Finance AG

Aug 2007 - Jul 2010

Zurich, Switzerland

Consultant, Senior Software Engineer

- Developed features for a securities lending product to service borrowing and lending, repo, synthetic finance, collateral management and risk management
 - ✓ Analyzed & estimated story points for user stories using poker estimation
 - ✓ Developed user stories using Core & Advanced Java
 - ✓ Wrote unit tests using JUnit

Investment Banks in London & Australia Sydney, Australia & Tonbridge, UK

Jan 2004 - Jul 2007

Consultant, Java Developer

- Maintenance of a Business forex service that facilitated transactions for import, export, foreign currency borrowings, foreign currency investments, profit & interest repatriation
 - ✓ Design of use cases and Use case diagrams using Rational Rose
 - √ System Testing and Bug Fixes

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

	Proficient	Competent	
Programming Languages	Java, Python, Javascript, SQL, Force.com, R	Obj-C, LAT _E X	
Machine Learning Toolkits	Scikit-Learn, Spark MLib	Graphlab	
Operating Systems	Linux, Unix, OS-X	Windows	
Platforms & Frameworks	iOS (Xcode), Express.io, Node.js, NLTK, Apache Spark	Spring, Hadoop	
Testing	JUnit, Frisby.js, Jasmine	PyUnit	
Version Control	Git, Subversion	CVS	
Tools & Utilities	Eclipse, Tableau, RStudio, OmniGraffle, Sublime	QFTest, Collabnet, TOAD	
Databases	MySQL, redis, SQLite, Oracle	DB2	
CRM	Salesforce		

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate	University	Grade	Earned Date
A Crash Course in Data Science	Johns Hopkins University on Coursera	100%	Oct 2015
Managing Data Analysis	Johns Hopkins University on Coursera	100%	Oct 2015
Data Science in Real Life	Johns Hopkins University on Coursera	95%	Oct 2015
Introduction to Big Data	University of California, San Diego on Coursera	96%	Oct 2015

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Certificate, Computer Programming

University of California (Extension), Santa Cruz, CA GPA: 4.0 Aug 2014

Project - Forecasting the severity of Seasonal Influenza using Supervised Machine Learning

Post Graduate Award, Mobile Application Development

University of California (Extension), Santa Cruz, CA GPA: 4.0

Aug 2014

Project - Loyalty Rewards Program for a Point of Sales System

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

PCCE, Goa, India 1st class Distinction with honors

Aug 2003

REFERENCES

References provided upon request. (Online references available at LinkedIn).